To write his 2010 book, The 5-Factor World Diet, nutritionist Harley Pasternak traveled to the healthiest countries around the world to learn more about what made their meals extra nourishing.
为了写作2010年出版的《5因素世界饮食》一书，营养学家哈利·帕斯特纳克走访了世界各地最健康的国家，想进一步了解是什么让这些国家的饭菜格外有营养。
He noted that Japanese people ate a wonderful variety of seaweeds, and that Chinese people tried to include at least five different colors in every meal.
他注意到，日本人吃的海藻种类之多令人赞叹，而中国人则力求每顿饭都至少包含五种不同的颜色。
Pasternak also came away with some valuable observations about how different the North American way of life was, compared with that of many other countries.
帕斯特纳克此行还带回了一些宝贵的观察心得：与许多其他国家的生活方式相比，北美的生活方式大不相同。
For starters, Americans eat much bigger portions than people in other countries.
首先，美国人吃的分量比其他国家的人大得多。
“We don’t prioritize eating seasonally or locally, and we also add lots of salt, sugar and thickening agents to our foods,” explained Pasternak.
“我们不优先考虑吃应季或本地的食物，还往食物里添加大量的盐、糖和增稠剂，”帕斯特纳克解释说。
Contrast that to the healthy Mediterranean, Nordic and Okinawan diets listed in Pasternak’s book.
与此形成对比的，是帕斯特纳克书中列出的几种健康饮食：地中海饮食、北欧饮食和冲绳饮食。
They all seem to stick to the ethos of regional, seasonal produce.
这些饮食似乎都保持着以本地区应季农产品为本的特质。
For example, a traditional Mediterranean diet includes fruits, vegetables, whole grains, nuts and olive oil as the main components of nutritional intake.
例如，传统的地中海饮食以水果、蔬菜、全谷物、坚果和橄榄油作为营养摄入的主要组成部分。
Fish, chicken and red wine make moderate appearances, while red meat, salt and sugar are used much less often.
鱼、鸡肉和红酒出现的频率适中，而红肉、盐和糖的使用频率则低得多。
The benefits of a traditional Mediterranean diet have been studied since the 1970s, and researchers have found that living that olive oil life can help people lose weight, lower their heart disease risk and reverse diabetes.
自20世纪70年代以来，人们一直在研究传统地中海饮食的益处；研究人员发现，过这种橄榄油式的生活能帮助人们减轻体重、降低患心脏病的风险并逆转糖尿病。
Most other healthy eating cultures also make meals an event—say, multiple courses around the family table, or a glass or two of red wine at a long lunch—as opposed to hastily wolfing down handfuls of cereal over the kitchen sink and calling it dinner.
其他大多数健康饮食文化也把吃饭当成一件大事，比如一家人围着餐桌吃上好几道菜，或是午餐吃上很久，其间喝上一两杯红酒，而不是对着厨房水槽匆匆狼吞虎咽几把麦片，就当是吃了晚饭。
Each of the healthy eating cultures has its own unique feature.
每种健康饮食文化都有自己独特的特点。
But Pasternak did take note of one unifying factor in most of the healthy societies he observed.
不过，帕斯特纳克确实注意到，他观察过的大多数健康社会都有一个共同因素。
“The only overlapping feature in most of these healthy countries is that they all walk way more than the average American,” said Pasternak.
“这些健康国家大多只有一个共同点，就是那里的人走路都比普通美国人多得多，”帕斯特纳克说。
“So really, regardless of what you’re eating, if someone’s walking four miles more than you each day, they’re going to be a lot thinner and live a lot longer than you.”
“所以说真的，不管你吃的是什么，如果有人每天比你多走四英里，那他就会比你瘦得多，也会比你长寿得多。”